TOKYO DAIICHI BANK HEADQUARTERS
（东京第一银行本部）
I don't wear a uniform,
我工作时不需要穿制服
so I wear clothes that will leave a good impression.
所以我都会挑给人留下好印象的私服
My motto is neat and tidy.
我的宗旨是干净利落
KEN SOMA
（相马健）
COMPANY NEWSLETTER
（《社内报导》）
I don't wear any accessories either.
我也不穿戴饰品
They get in the way when I run.
不然奔跑的时候会碍事
Run?
奔跑？
It happens once in a while.
偶尔会有这种情况啦
-I see. -Any other questions?
-原来如此 -还有其他问题吗？
No. Shall we go to the lobby to take pictures?
没了 那我们去大大厅拍照吧
Sure.
好的
Let me touch up my makeup again.
我先去补妆哦
I am Mai Hanasaki. My motto is neat and tidy.
我是花琦舞 我的宗旨是干净利落
She's getting carried away.
真是得意忘形啊
-Ms. Hanasaki. -Yes.
-花琦小姐 -是
-Please be normal. -Okay, then.
-普通的姿势就好了 -好吧
How about this?
那这样呢？
Hanasaki. This is only a company newsletter.
我说花琦啊 这只是《社内报导》
But it'll be distributed to all the branches nationwide.
但这可是要发到全国各分行的
Sorry. How about this one next?
不好意思 这样可以吗？
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR TSUYOSHI SHINDO
（常务执行董事 真藤毅）
Good morning, Executive Director Shindo.
早安 真藤常务
Good morning.
早
This is a photoshoot for the company newsletter.
这是《社内报导》的拍摄
This is an article about female employees.
是女性职员的特辑版面吧？
Yes. It just so happens that I'm going to be featured this month.
对 刚好这次轮到我登上这个版面了
I hear you're doing a good job these days.
最近你挺活跃的嘛
Thanks.
谢谢
Branch Inspection is doing unnecessary things again.
分行稽核班那班人真是多管闲事
A company that has women actively taking initiative,
一个企业要是有积极主动的女性职员
has better future prospects.
才会有更好的前景
Thank you very much.
谢谢
-Let's go, Mr. Kodama. -Yes.
-走吧 儿玉 -是
He praised me.
他表扬我耶
It's about time you learn how to read between the lines.
你也该学会听懂话中话了吧？
-Let's keep going. -You're taking more?
-那我们继续吧 -还要拍？
Please go ahead.
拜托了
Hello.
喂？
Where are you guys?
你们去哪儿了？
What's wrong, Mr. Shibasaki?
怎么了 芝崎次长？
There's trouble.
大事不好了
Please go to the Machida Branch right now.
你们能去一趟町田分行吗？
What?
什么？
URGENT CASE:
（分行稽核指示）
INVESTIGATE A FEMALE STALKING VICTIM IN THE FINANCE DEPARTMENT
（融资课女性职员被跟踪）
-Stalker?
-跟踪狂？
Yes. A female employee at Machida Branch is being stalked.
对 听说町田分行的 某位女性职员被跟踪了
That's awful. Stalking is a mean and malicious crime.
好过分 跟踪狂是最恶劣 最卑鄙的犯罪
An enemy to all women.
是全世界女性的公敌
But why do we have to go?
但是为什么要我们去？
Right. Why don't they report it to the police?
对啊 不是应该要报警吗？
-Right? -Well, it's complicated.
-是吧？ -这件事不是这么简单
What do you mean?
什么意思？
I see. The stalker might be one of our employees?
是因为那个跟踪狂 可能是我们银行的职员吧？
-What? -It's something like that.
-什么？ -很可能就是这样
I can't believe there's a stalker among us!
我们银行里竟然有这种人
We don't know yet.
还不确定呢
It's bad if our employee is a stalker,
如果犯人是银行职员就麻烦了
so they want it solved quietly.
所以他们想内部解决
They want to sweep it under the rug, huh?
是想息事宁人吧？
That's typical of top management.
的确是高层会干的事呢
Don't get worked up so early in the morning.
别一大早就这么大火气啦
You don't understand how stressful it is for female employees
你们根本不明白 在以男性为主的社会工作的女性职员
who are working in a male-dominated society.
抱着多大的压力
They say that it is time for women to shine,
说什么这是女性闪耀的时代
but they're being stalked. How horrible.
结果在职场遇到跟踪狂 太糟糕了
There aren't many men who would have the guts to stalk Ms. Hanasaki.
不过 应该没人有胆子跟踪花琦吧
She's so scary.
因为太恐怖了啊
What did you say?
你们说什么呢？
-Nothing.
-没什么
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK MACHIDA BRANCH
（东京第一银行町田分行）
-Hello. -Thank you for waiting.
-欢迎光临 -久等了
I want to withdraw cash.
请帮我提款
I've only heard of stalkers on the news.
跟踪狂这种词 只有在电视新闻里听过啊
I can't believe it's happening in our branch.
没想到会发生在我们分行
It was very unexpected.
真是难以置信
I didn't want to report it to headquarters,
我本来不想上报本部的
but our employee made such a big deal, that I had no choice.
但我们的员工闹得很厉害 实在没有办法
I understand.
明白
I was wondering who would be sent from Branch Inspection at headquarters but…
还以为分行稽核班会来什么人物呢
Nice to meet you.
请多多指教
You haven't reported this to the police?
请问这事报警了吗？
Doing that will give this branch a bad reputation.
要是报警的话 会损害分行的声誉
Why do you think that we called you?
不然 我们为什么找你们啊？
The victim is suspicious of her colleagues,
被害人怀疑是同事干的
so we want to keep it quiet.
所以我们不想把事情闹大
I see.
原来如此
It's such a big pain during this busy season.
现在繁忙期还出这种乱子
I agree.
就是说啊
That's why I was against having a woman in the Finance Department.
所以 我之前 才会反对女性职员进入融资课嘛
We had no trouble like this before.
以前根本不会有这种麻烦
With all due res--
请恕我…
Please talk to her directly.
你们直接跟她谈谈吧
Please don't make this into a big deal.
请千万不要把事情闹大
Yes.
知道了
What's wrong with those two?
这两个人是怎么回事？
Branch Manager hates trouble,
经理怕麻烦
and the Section Chief is sexist.
而课长歧视女性
I understand, so calm down.
我明白 但你先冷静啊
They don't care about the female employee who is a victim.
他们一点都不在乎 受害女性的心情吧？
I understand, so lower your voice!
我知道了 你小声一点啦
I am Maehara.
我是前原
I've been in the Finance Department since two years ago.
我两年前开始在这里的融资课工作
You were hired by our bank ten years ago.
你十年前受聘于本行
Starting at Otemachi Branch, you went to Jiyugaoka Branch for three years,
一开始在大手町分行 然后在自由之丘分行
and three years at Kawasaki Branch.
和川崎分行融资课 各做了三年
You are an elite.
你很优秀啊
Not at all.
过奖了
The Finance Department is a male-dominant workplace.
不过 融资课是以男性为中心的部门吧？
Isn't it tough as the only female employee?
身为唯一的女职员 不会很辛苦吗？
No, it's okay.
这倒还好
I can tell that it's not easy to work with those managers.
我觉得在那些经理手下工作 肯定很辛苦吧？
I manage it somehow.
我还能应付
We hear that you are being stalked.
我们听说你被跟踪狂跟踪了
Yes.
是的
Will you please tell us the details?
能告诉我们细节吗？
It started about three months ago.
是大概三个月前开始的
Hello?
喂？
First, it was a silent phone call.
一开始是无声电话
I started receiving several calls a week at night.
那时每周有好几次在深夜时打来
UNKNOWN CALLER
（未知来电）
Just when the calls finally stopped…
之后 终于没再打来了
Someone started following me on my way back home.
却开始有人在我回家的路上跟踪我
You didn't see the stalker's face?
你没有看到对方的脸吗？
I was so scared that I couldn't see.
我太害怕了 不敢看
I understand.
我理解
But it didn't stop there.
但不仅如此
What else?
还有其他的吗？
Last Friday, someone broke into my apartment.
上周五 有人偷偷闯入我家了
What?
什么？
There was trouble that day at work,
那天 我在工作上遇到了一点麻烦
so I came home after midnight.
凌晨才回到家
I knew something was off the moment I stepped inside.
我一进到屋里就觉得有些不对劲
My slippers were not aligned.
我的拖鞋放歪了
Is that all?
这样而已吗？
-Could it be your mistake? -Mr. Soma.
-不是你的错觉吗？ -相马
No.
不是的
I always straighten my slippers at the front door before I leave.
我出门的时候 一定会把玄关的拖鞋摆好
It's a habit.
这是我的习惯
My dad does that too.
我爸爸也是这样
Was there anything stolen?
有什么东西失窃吗？
Luckily, nothing was stolen.
幸好没有什么东西失窃
I checked my accessories, cash,
我的首饰 现金
and underwear.
还有内衣裤都在
But I have no doubt that someone entered my room.
但我确定有人进去过
There are things that only you can notice.
有些细节只有本人才会察觉呢
Wait a minute.
请等一下
What happened to the key to your house? Was it locked?
你家的门锁呢？是锁着的吗？
That's the point.
就是这一点
That's why I doubt my colleagues.
我才怀疑是我的同事
What do you mean?
什么意思？
I had lost my key that day.
我那天把家里钥匙弄不见了
So I went to get the spare key from my sister who lives nearby.
我还去找了住在附近的姐姐 拿备用钥匙
But now that I think about it, I don't think I lost it.
现在想起来 我想不是不见了
I think someone in this branch stole it.
而是被分行的某个人偷走了
That's why you told the Branch Manager that you want to report it.
所以你才会跟春日经理说你想报警
Yes.
是的
Do you have any idea who it might be?
你有怀疑的人吗？
Well… I can't say for certain.
这个我也不太确定
Section Chief told me that I'm probably imagining things.
小见山课长也说只是我的错觉
We're on your side, Ms. Maehara. Please don't worry.
我门是站在你这一边的 放心吧
We will keep what you said a secret.
我们会保守秘密的
We will help you as much as possible.
我们会尽力帮你的
Thank you very much.
真的很谢谢你们
I think it is someone in the Finance Department.
我怀疑是融资课的某个人
I always keep my bag under my desk.
我平常都把包包放在桌子下
That's the only way my key could have gotten stolen.
只有课内的人才偷得到钥匙
Beside Ms. Maehara, there are nine people.
除了前原小姐以外 融资课有九个人
Let's ask everyone.
我们找每个人问话吧
What are you talking about?
你说什么呢？
What are you going to do?
你想干嘛？
Are you going to ask each person if they are stalking Ms. Maehara?
你打算一个个去问他们 是不是在跟踪前原小姐吗？
Good point.
说得也是
If there is a criminal among them, we'll be making him wary.
要是他们之中有犯人 这样只会打草惊蛇
We shouldn't tell them that we're Branch Inspection.
我们还得隐瞒分行稽核班的身分
I see.
这样啊
I have a good idea.
我有个好主意
FINANCE DEPARTMENT NAOKI WADA
（融资课 和田直树）
You're HR?
你们是人事部？
-Yes.
-对
We are visiting all the branches talking to everyone
我们正在走访各个分行 跟职员聊天
about ways to improve the workplace.
藉此改善职场环境
Today, we are asking people in the Finance Department.
这一次是以融资课的各位为对象
I see.
原来如此
Do you have any problems or complaints these days?
请问你最近 有感到困扰或是不满的事情吗？
Not in particular.
并没有
How are people in the Finance Department?
融资课内的人际关系如何？
No problem.
没有问题
We have good teamwork under Mr. Komiyama.
我们在小见山课长的带领下 工作很有默契
That sounds wonderful.
那真是太好了
Stop staring, Hanasaki.
你盯得太明显了
I have lots to say to HR.
我有很多想要跟人事部说的事呢
My colleagues are promoted accordingly,
跟我同期入社的同事都升职了
but why haven't I moved up to the manager position?
为什么我还没升到经理的位置呢？
Well…
这个嘛…
It isn't fair!
这不公平啊！
You'll never understand.
你们不明白的
Do you know how many years I've been waiting?
你们知道我等多少年了吗？
HR never understood me to begin with.
人事部根本不了解我的情况
You don't understand me at all.
你们什么都不了解
Ms. Maehara seems to be working hard as the only female employee.
前原小姐是课内唯一的女性 工作很努力
How do you view her as a colleague?
你认为她的工作能力如何？
I think she is very competent.
我觉得她很能干
She's very cognizant about the people around her,
她很照顾身边的人
so I learn a lot from her.
我从她身上学到了很多
What else?
还有呢？
That's all.
没了 就这样
Are you sure?
真的吗？
That's all for today. Thank you for your cooperation.
今天就到此为止 谢谢你的合作
Excuse me.
那我先出去了
Hey.
你啊
Stop making things so obvious.
不要那么明显好不好？
I'm sorry. I couldn't help it.
抱歉 我控制不住
There were so many times when I almost asked, "Aren't you the stalker?"
我有好几次差点要问说 “你是不是那个跟踪狂？”
Thanks for not asking.
谢谢你没问出口啊
-Let's move on. -Okay.
-继续吧 -好
So you're saying that you didn't find any employee that was suspicious.
所以 你们觉得 面谈的职员都没什么可疑的？
Right. For today.
从今天的对话来看 是的
-Hard to tell from an interview-- -Are you satisfied?
-不 过 很难从一次的… -你满意了吧？
We even bothered Branch Inspection, but there was nothing.
都劳烦分行稽核班了 还是没什么结果
Let's close this case, okay?
这件事到此为止 可以吧？
Nothing good will come from making this into a bigger problem.
即使把这件事闹大 也不会有什么好处的
Maehara.
前原
Branch Manager is saying this with your best interest in mind.
春日经理可是为了你好才这么说的
Yes.
是
Isn't this stalker just in your imagination to begin with?
这跟踪狂的事 会不会只是你想太多啊？
Imagination?
想太多？
There are excessively self-conscious women
常常有自我意识过剩的女性
who mistake others as gropers on the train.
在电车里误会别人性骚扰啊
Try to understand the people who have to deal with your paranoia.
旁人还要应付你的多疑 你也多体谅一下啊
Worst-case scenario,
在最坏的情况下
you could have turned your colleagues into criminals.
你会把你的同事们冤枉成罪犯的
I am sorry.
很抱歉
-With all due respect-- -Hanasaki.
-请恕我直言 你… -花琦
Ms. Maehara, you have no time for this, right?
前原 你可没闲工夫搞这些事情吧？
You should be thinking of the future.
你应该多想想将来
You can't stay here forever, after all.
毕竟你也不可能一直待在这里啊
-What do you mean-- -Anyway.
-什么意思？ -总之
This case is closed.
这件事到此为止
Yes.
是
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
（花琦居酒屋）
One more beer.
再来一瓶
What's wrong? You seem to be having a rough day.
怎么了？心情不好啊？
Did something happen again?
又发生什么事了吗？
Yes, this and that.
说不清楚呢
Did my daughter cause you any trouble?
我女儿给你带来麻烦了吗？
Not at all.
不是的
I'm the one causing trouble.
是我给她带来麻烦
-Is that so? -Yes.
-是吗？ -嗯
This dish is our specialty.
这是我们的招牌菜
The ultimate eggplant.
至尊茄子
Specially made for the beautiful lady.
是只为美女特别制作的料理
-Just for her? -Thank you very much.
-只给她吗？ -谢谢你
You're so weak with pretty girls.
对美女真是没辙啊
What's wrong with that?
有什么问题吗？
Mr. Kozo, beer please.
幸三 啤酒
Okay. Please enjoy.
来了 请慢用
I am sorry that I couldn't be of any help.
没帮上你的忙 真是对不起
No. I really appreciate you both.
不 我真的很感激你们
Despite what Branch Manager said, we will continue the investigation.
就算春日经理那样说 我们还是会继续调查的
There she goes again.
又来了
I can't believe sexist people like Mr. Komiyama still exist.
不敢相信现在这个年代 还有小见山课长那样性别歧视的人呢
Does he know the time he's living in? It's 2015.
他以为这是什么年代啊？ 现在都2015年了
I'm used to it.
我都习惯了
Don't get used to it.
别习惯这些
Someone has to teach him a lesson.
总得有人给他点教训
Must be nice for you, since you always teach people lessons without holding back.
你真好啊 总是不收敛地到处给人教训
What?
什么？
Sometimes I hold back and endure the situation too.
我有时也会忍住 吞下想说的话的
Like when?
什么时候？
I held my fist like this and endured it earlier.
我刚刚也是这样握紧拳头忍下来了
My nails were sticking into my palm.
手指甲都快要掐进手掌了
It's true that patience is necessary when working under Mr. Komiyama.
确实在小见山课长手下工作 是需要忍耐的
He hasn't liked me ever since I was assigned to the Machida Branch.
从我被分配到町田分行开始 他就不怎么喜欢我
Really?
是吗？
He always found a way to pick on me.
他总是挑我的毛病
So you're saying that there was an error in my judgement?
你是说我的判断是错的吗？
-No, I just-- -Don't make excuses!
-不是 我只是… -别找藉口了
I am sorry.
对不起
You probably got carried away because people
大概是川崎分行的人都对你很好
treated you well at the Kawasaki Branch.
你就得意忘形了吧？
But I won't go easy on you just because you're a woman.
我可不会因为你是女的就惯着你
How dare he say such a thing!
他怎么可以这么说？
Was he always like that?
他一直都这样吗？
I heard from my senior
我从前辈那里听说
that Mr. Komiyama was beaten to a promotion by a female colleague.
小见山课长曾被同期的女同事 抢去升迁的机会
They say he was probably not happy about that.
他可能因为那件事不太愉快
That makes no sense.
这不合理啊
So he's being mean to you just because you're a woman?
因为你是女生 就对你如此过分吗？
How pathetic.
真是可悲
He can't help it.
没办法啊
His colleagues were all promoted but he's the only one that's a Section Chief.
同期都晋升了 只有他还在课长职位上一动也不动
As you saw, the Branch Manager is younger than him too.
你也看到了 春日经理也比他年轻
-He can't help but be bitter. -Even so…
-他当然会妒忌了 -但是…
By the way, when the Branch Manager told you
对了 春日经理说
"You can't stay here forever,"
“你不可能一直待在这里”
what did he mean?
是什么意思？
Do you know the company Aoyama Kengyou?
你们听说过青山建业吗？
Aoyama Kengyou?
青山建业？
It is a construction company that recently went bankrupt.
好像是最近刚倒闭的一家建设公司
I was in charge of financing that company.
那家公司的融资是我负责的
How much was it?
金额是多少？
In total, 300 million yen.
总金额是三亿日元
Among that, the uncollectible amount is 200 million yen.
其中不能回收的金额达到两亿日元
-Two hundred million yen? -Oh no.
-两亿？ -天啊
I have to take responsibility.
我需要为此负责
I'm sure I'll be sent somewhere during the next rotation.
所以下次人事调动 我恐怕会被调走
I see.
这样啊
I always worked hard
我一直以来那么拼命
so that people would not look down on me for being a woman.
不让人因为我是女人就轻视我
I didn't think I'd fall at a place like this.
真的想不到我会在这里受挫
It's not fair.
真过分
She was in charge of the loan to the company that went bankrupt.
她负责处理融资的公司倒闭了
That's more than enough reason to be demoted.
单单这个理由就足以让她被降职了
One X-mark can end everything.
一子错 满盘皆落索
-That's how a bank works. Right? -That's right.
-这就是银行的作风 对吧？ -没错
That slogan is wrong.
这标语是不对的
It's not a slogan.
这不是标语啦
The bank must be a tough place.
银行还真是复杂的地方啊
This is on us.
这个 请你吃的
-Are you sure? -Yes, of course.
-真的吗？ -当然了
Thank you.
谢谢你
Please come to my restaurant anytime.
欢迎随时再光顾哦
Dad, you are smiling too much.
爸 你也笑得太开心了吧？
It looks delicious.
看起来真好吃
You can't feel at ease until the stalker is caught, huh?
一天没逮到那跟踪狂 你就无法安心吧？
You are right.
就是说啊
How are you being followed when you go home from the office?
你在下班回家路上被跟踪的情况 是怎样的？
Well…
这个嘛
I usually notice on my way home from the station.
我通常是从车站 到公寓的那条路上察觉到的
What day of the week?
通常是星期几？
Well, Wednesday is more likely because there's no overtime.
好像都是周三比较常发生 那天都不用加班
Tomorrow is Wednesday, isn't it?
明天就是周三啊
I know what you are thinking.
我知道你想做什么
Mr. Soma, let's do a stakeout.
相马 我们暗中监视吧
Are you trying to follow her like a detective?
监视？你又以为你是刑警吗？
You're not going to do anything?
难道你想置之不理吗？
Ms. Maehara is so scared.
前原小姐都这么害怕了
No, but…
不是啦
Mr. Soma, you said that you would help her as much as you can.
相马 你说过会尽力帮助她的
Was that touching statement a lie?
那种令人感动的话原来只是慌言吗？
-It's not a lie. -Then help her.
-不是慌言啦 -那就帮她啊
No, I can't trouble you like that.
不用了 我不想给你们添麻烦
Don't worry. Let's find the stalker together.
没关系 我们一起捉住那个跟踪狂吧
Thank you.
谢谢你们
You must be kidding.
别开玩笑了啦
Hanasaki speaking.
我是花琦
This is Shibasaki. I am in position. Over.
我是芝崎 已经就位了
Roger. Thank you.
收到 拜托你了
Why did you invite Mr. Shibasaki?
你为什么连芝崎次长都叫来了啊？
I didn't. But he said he wanted to join when I talked to him.
不是我叫的 是他听了我的汇报之后自己要加入的
Apparently, Mr. Shibasaki wanted to be a detective when he was a child.
看来芝崎次长从小就想当一名刑警啊
Don't look.
别这样看人家
I couldn't say no to him.
我无法拒绝他啊
Here she comes.
来了
She left the office.
前原小姐出来了
I will follow her to see if there is anyone suspicious. Over.
我会跟踪她看看有什么可疑的人
Roger.
收到
I'm sorry.
对不起
-What is it? -I'm sorry.
-干什么啊？ -对不起
I can't believe it.
真不敢相信
Oh?
嗯？
Hey.
你别走
-This is Hanasaki. Any news? -Sorry, I lost track of her.
-我是花琦 有什么发现吗？ -抱歉 我跟丢了
-Lost track?
-跟丢了？
I'm busy right now. I'll leave the rest to you.
我现在有点事呢 接下来就拜托你们了
He hung up.
他挂电话了
I didn't expect much from him to begin with.
我一开始对他就没抱太大期望
Message from Ms. Maehara. She's arrived at the station.
是前原小姐传来的讯息 说她到车站了
I wonder if the stalker will appear.
跟踪狂真的会出现吗？
I don't know if things will work out so well.
就是说啊 会这么顺利逮到吗？
Here comes another message.
她又传讯息来了
She said someone is following her.
她说好像有人在跟着她
Here it comes.
来了
Let's go.
走
KEEP WALKING - HANASAKI
（花琦：一直往前走）
Wait for me.
等一下啦
Excuse me.
不好意思
Wait!
给我站住
Garbage?
垃圾？
You can't run away from us.
你逃不掉了
You are…
你是…
Mr. Furuhashi?
古桥先生？
What's going on? Explain yourself.
你解释一下到底是怎么回事
What are you doing?
你这是在做什么？
I liked Ms. Maehara for a long time.
我一直都很喜欢前原
But she wasn't interested in me.
但她对我总是不理不睬
Do you think that's going to be a good enough excuse?
那你就跟踪人家吗？
This is going to be a hassle.
真是麻烦啊
I am sorry.
很抱歉
What were you trying to do by following her?
你跟着前原 想要做什么？
Nothing.
不做什么
I just wanted to see her.
我只是想看看她而已
Was it you who made the silent calls to her?
打无声电话的也是你吧？
Yes.
是的
Do you know what you have done?
你知道你自己做了什么吗？
Ms. Maehara has been scared for a long time.
前原小姐一直在担惊受怕呢
I am sorry.
真的很对不起
You even entered her room. That's horrible.
你甚至还闯入她家 太过分了
What?
什么？
Don't play dumb.
别装傻了
You entered Ms. Maehara's room without permission last Friday.
你上周五 擅自闯入前原小姐的公寓了吧？
No, I didn't.
不 我没有
You're not going to admit it?
事到如今 你还不承认？
I don't want to have to say this,
我也不想这么说
but the police can uncover everything.
不过 只要警察一调查 就会水落石出
I didn't enter her room. Please believe me.
我真的没有进过她家 请相信我
Furuhashi!
古桥！
I really didn't.
我真的没有
Anyway, stay home until we decide how to deal with you.
总之 在处分决定之前 给我乖乖待在家里
Do you understand?
明白了吗？
Yes.
是
I see.
这样啊
Thank you very much.
真是谢谢你们
No worries.
没什么
Will Mr. Furuhashi be fired?
古桥会被解雇吗？
I don't know yet.
还不知道
But since he admitted to stalking you,
不过 他承认了自己的跟踪行为
he will have a big X-mark on his career as a banker.
职业生涯上 肯定会留下大大的污点吧？
There's something that bothers me about this.
可是我总觉得哪里不对劲
Mr. Furuhashi admitted that he stalked her,
古桥先生都承认自己跟踪了
but why didn't he admit that he entered the room?
为什么就是不承认进过公寓呢？
He didn't admit it?
他没有承认吗？
If he admits to breaking and entering, he will be punished more severely.
如果承认私闯民宅 那会罪加一等啊
But I think he made the situation worse by denying it.
但是 否认的话 不是更糟糕吗？
Don't you think it's better for him to admit everything?
全盘托出难道不是对他比较有利吗？
Hey, don't say things that will worry Ms. Maehara even more.
别再说这些让前原小姐更不安的话了
I'm sorry. It was nothing but my personal opinion.
抱歉 那只是我的想法
This is all we can report. Sorry to disturb you at night.
我们都说完了 不好意思那么晚打扰你
Thank you.
谢谢
Excuse me.
那我们告辞了
You were working until this late?
你这么晚了还在工作啊？
These are financial documents for Aoyama Kengyou.
这是青山建业的财务资料
Didn't Aoyama Kengyou go bankrupt already?
青山建业不是破产了吗？
Yes.
是的
I know I'm not supposed to bring these documents home,
我知道我不应该把资料带回家
but I made a copy before it was sent to headquarters.
但我在资料送到本部之前复印了一份
For what?
为什么？
I suspect Aoyama Kengyou of planned bankruptcy.
因为我怀疑青山建业是计划性破产
Planned bankruptcy?
-计划性破产？
You mean they deceived the bank and went bankrupt on purpose?
你是说他们欺骗银行 故意破产吗？
What did Branch Manager or Komiyama say?
春日经理和小见山课长怎么说？
They didn't take me seriously.
他们根本不当一回事
Do you have any evidence of planned bankruptcy?
你有证据证明是计划性破产吗？
Not yet.
还没有
I want to investigate it.
我想调查一下
What do you think, Mr. Komiyama?
小见山课长 你怎么看？
I checked the financial documents, but I didn't see anything suspicious.
那些财务资料我都看过了 我不认为有什么可疑的
I think she's reading too much into it.
应该是前原多虑了吧？
No way…
不是的
That's what the Section Chief is saying, so it's settled.
课长都这么说了 那就是没问题了
-However-- -You.
-但是… -你…
You just don't want to
只是不想
take responsibility for the 200-million-yen loss.
为了那两亿日元的损失负责吧？
That's not it.
不是这样的
Anyway, this case regarding Aoyama Kengyou will be sent
总之 青山建业的案子
to the Debt Recovery Department at headquarters.
将会被送往本部的债权回收部
This is a decision by the Branch Manager.
这是分行经理的决定
You will take responsibility
而你身为该项融资的负责人
as the one who was in charge of the loan.
必须为此承担相应的责任
It was no use, whatever I said.
我说什么都无济于事
So you made a copy of the financial documents to
所以你就复印了一份财务资料
investigate it in secret.
想要私自调查？
I don't think the Debt Recovery Department
我觉得债权回收部不会弄清楚
will clarify the flow of funds.
资金流向
But I haven't found any evidence regarding the planned bankruptcy either.
可是 我又还没有找到 计划性破产的证据
Can I see the document?
我能看一下资料吗？
Here.
请看
It may be hard to believe, but Mr. Soma used to be a capable worker
也许很难相信 不过 相马以前可是融资部内
in the Finance Department.
很优秀的员工哦
No need to say, "hard to believe."
什么叫“很难相信”啊？
It seems like a page was ripped off here.
这里有一页被撕掉了
Do you remember what was there?
你记得这一页是什么吗？
I made an index.
对了 我做了目录
Please wait a moment.
请等一下
LIST OF TRANSFER ACCOUNTS
（汇款账户清单）
What's missing is the list of accounts for the transfers.
被撕掉的好像是汇款账户的清单
When did you see this last?
你最后一次见到清单是什么时候？
When I made a copy last week.
是上周复印的时候
Mr. Soma, what's wrong?
相马 怎么了？
It might not be Mr. Furuhashi who entered this room.
闯入这房子的也许不是古桥
What?
什么？
What do you mean?
什么意思？
This is a completely separate case from the stalker.
这与跟踪案是完全不一样的案件啊
The target for the break-in was not Ms. Maehara,
闯入公寓的犯人不是为了前原小姐
but this document.
而是为了这个资料
He knew that you were investigating
他知道你正在调查
the planned bankruptcy by Aoyama Kengyou
青山建业的计划性破产一事
and tried to steal the document secretly.
就想潜进来把资料偷走
Then the person who entered here is someone from Aoyama Kengyou?
你是说闯进来的是青山建业的人？
I don't know yet.
这个还不确定
But there's a reason why the culprit didn't want you to see that list.
但犯人不想让你看到那个清单 肯定是有理由的
The original document was sent to
资料的原件
the Debt Recovery Department at headquarters, right?
被送去本部的债权回收部了 是吧？
Yes.
是的
If we see that, we may be able to find out something.
如果看了那个 也许就能知道什么了
Let's check it out.
我们查查看吧
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
I can't believe Furuhashi was the stalker.
真没想到古桥就是那个跟踪狂啊
People are never what they appear to be.
真是人不可貌相
Good morning.
早安
DEBT RECOVERY DEPARTMENT
（债权回收部）
Here it is.
就是这个
What is it?
怎么回事啊？
We just want to check something. I am sorry.
我们只是想查查看 真不好意思
It's not in here.
没有啊
Not in here, either.
我这里也没有
What's happening?
怎么回事呢？
The transfer account list
那张汇款账户清单
was removed at the Machida Branch.
应该是在町田分行就被拿掉了
It means that Aoyama Kengyou has an accomplice in the branch.
也就是说 町田分行有青山建业的同伙？
Yes.
没错
-An accomplice? -Yes.
-同伙？ -是的
We think someone in Machida Branch is working with the culprit.
我们认为町田分行里有人与罪犯共谋
No way.
不会吧？
Who knows that you took
还有谁知道
Aoyama Kengyou's financial documents home?
你把青山建业的财务资料拿回家？
Everyone in the Finance Department knows.
融资课的人都知道
I told them during a meeting that I made a copy to investigate it.
我在一次会议上 说了要复印资料进行调查的事
Who gave you permission to do that?
是谁允许你这么做了？
Section Chief was very upset.
小见山课长很生气
Then everyone in the Finance Department can be a suspect.
那就是说融资课的所有人都有嫌疑啊
You are right.
确实是这样
The accomplice took the list of transfer accounts before…
那个同伙…
AOYAMA KENGYOU
（青山建业）
…Aoyama Kengyou's financial documents were sent to headquarters.
…在青山建业的财务资料 被送到本部前 拿掉了汇款账户清单
Later on, when he found out that you had made a copy,
之后 他发现你复印了资料
he secretly stole your house keys
就趁你不注意 偷了你的家门锁匙
and entered your room to take away the same page from the document.
闯进了你家 偷偷撕掉了那一页清单
I can't believe it.
真是难以相信
Who did such a thing?
是谁做的呢？
We will continue to investigate.
我们会继续调查的
Will you please keep this a secret?
这件事请你保密
I will.
我知道了
Mr. Soma. What's your plan?
相马 现在怎么办？
Let's go to Aoyama Kengyou.
我门去一趟青山建业吧
-We might find an employee. -Okay.
-也许还有职员在那儿 -好的
An accomplice?
同伙？
Yes.
是的
We think someone in Machida Branch is working with the culprit.
我门认为町田分行里有人与罪犯共谋
Maehara.
前原
You look lost.
你发什么呆呢？
I am sorry.
对不起
We're missing one employee because of someone. Work hard.
现在因为某人才少了一个人手 给我用心工作啊
-Yes. -Damn. This is such a hassle for us.
-是 -真是的 只会给我门添麻烦
Aren't you partly responsible for the way Furuhashi acted?
毕竟古桥会做出那种事 你也是有责任的吧？
Am I right?
对吧？
Is that so. I see.
这样啊 我知道了
How was it?
怎么样？
They said they can't distribute the documents to individual creditors.
他们说不能把资料交给个别债权者
That's the right answer for a lawyer.
律师也只能这么回答我们了
I see.
这样啊
I guess we have to do it the hard way.
这样一来就只能用吃力的办法了
Do you know of a way?
什么办法？
No…
办法嘛
but maybe yes.
也是有的
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
BRANCH INSPECTION
（分行稽核班）
Um…
什么意思？
This is Aoyama Kengyou's transfer data for the last year.
这些是青山建业 过去这一年的转账记录
Are we going to check all this?
我们要全部查一遍吗？
I told you that it was the hard way.
我说了啊 是吃力不讨好的办法
This is too hard.
这也太吃力了吧？
The transfer account was taken away because there's an
转账清单会被偷走
account that they don't want to be seen.
表示那上面有个不能被发现的账户
It's in here.
而那个账户就在这里
We must do it.
只能这样了
Let's find any suspicious account.
我们找找可疑的账户吧
Although it'll be like finding a needle in a haystack.
虽然这就像海底捞针一样难
Let's check every single one in the database.
要一个不剩地查完这些档案哦
Okay.
好的
HARAKAWA TRADING COMPANY
（原川物产）
HARIMOTO HOUSING
（张本房产）
BRAIN INSTITUTE
（布莱恩研究所）
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK MACHIDA BRANCH
（东京第一银行町田分行）
You checked all the transfer accounts for Aoyama Kengyou?
你们检查了青山建业 所有的汇款账户？
Yes. It was really hard, but it was worth it.
对 虽然很吃力 但总算有收获
We found one account that does not exist in our database.
我们发现了一个 没在我们的资料库里登录的收款账户
We investigated that company and found out that
经调查之后发现
it has a connection with someone in the Machida Branch.
那与町田分行的某位人员有所关联
It means that Aoyama Kengyou was paying money to someone
也就是说青山建业把钱转给了
at the Machida Branch.
町田分行的那位人员
Who was it?
那个人是谁？
We will tell you in person, Ms. Maehara.
我们想当面告诉你 前原小姐
We will be there.
我们马上到
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
Branch Manager. Please check this.
春日经理 你看看这个
Thank you very much.
谢谢
Excuse me.
打扰了
What's the matter?
请问有何贵干？
The disciplinary action for Mr. Yoichi Furuhashi was announced today.
对古桥洋一的处分已经决定了
I wanted to let you know.
我们想过来告知各位
-What? -Really?
-什么？ -是吗？
Yes.
是的
What is the disciplinary action?
那是什么处分？
Official warning.
警告
An official warning?
警告？
Is that all?
就这样吗？
A transfer is being discussed as well.
应该也会被调职
What's wrong?
有什么问题吗？
No. I'm surprised that it's not very serious.
没有 只是处分不是很重 我有点惊讶
Wait a minute.
等一下
Furuhashi broke into Maehara's house.
古桥可是闯进了前原的家里啊
It could become a criminal case.
这算是刑事犯罪吧？
I thought he'd be dismissed.
我还以为他会被解雇呢
Of course, the breaking and entering will be a criminal case.
没错 私闯民宅确实是刑事犯罪
He's going to the police as an employee?
那他会以职员身分被移送法办吗？
No.
不会
I don't understand at all.
这我就搞不懂了
He has to take responsibility for what he has done.
他必须为自己做过的事负责啊
We have to set an example for the other employees.
不然怎么给其他职员警惕呢？
The person who broke into Ms. Maehara's house was not Mr. Furuhashi.
闯入前原小姐家里的并不是古桥先生
What?
什么？
Then who was it?
那会是谁？
It was you, Mr. Komiyama.
那就是你 小见山课长
Don't talk nonsense!
胡说
Why would I do that?
我干嘛要干这种事？
To destroy the evidence of your
为了消除
connection with Aoyama Kengyou.
你与青山建业的来往证据
Is that true, Mr. Komiyama?
是真的吗 小见山课长？
No! I had nothing to do with that.
不是 没这回事
We think Aoyama Kengyou's bankruptcy was planned.
我们认为青山建业的破产 是预先计划好的
The president is most likely hiding his funds somewhere.
社长应该是把资产藏到了某处
Mr. Komiyama knew that fact
小见山课长深知此事的真相
but purposely overlooked it
却故意隐瞒
and received money in return.
还收取贿赂作为回报
You took the list of transfer accounts
你从分行的青山建业文件夹里
from Aoyama Kengyou's documents located at this branch.
拿走了汇款账户清单
You stole Ms. Maehara's house key.
然後后偷走前原小姐的家门锁匙
You entered her room and ripped out the account list.
偷偷潜入她家撕掉清单
You did all of that.
这全是你做的
It's a lie.
胡说八道
That's all just your imagination.
这只是你们的想像而已
Unfortunately, it's not our imagination.
很遗憾 这并不是我们的想像
We investigated to see what was on
我们已经调查过了
Aoyama Kengyou's transfer account list
你想尽办法隐瞒的那份
that you tried so hard to hide.
青山建业的汇款账户清单
There is a consulting company called Brain Institute.
上面有一家 叫布莱恩研究所的顾问公司
I'm sure you know it.
我想你应该知道
It has no business history.
这家公司没有任何实际业务
It's like a dummy company.
是一家空壳公司
Aoyama Kengyou transferred five million yen to this company
青山建业给这家公司 汇入了五百万日元
as a consultation fee.
作为顾问费用
The name of the president is Sayoko Komiyama.
其董事长的名字是小见山佐代子
Mr. Komiyama, she is your wife.
正是你的夫人呢 小见山课长
If this company and the transfer comes to light,
一旦被人发现有资金流入这家公司
so will your connection with Aoyama Kengyou.
你与青山建业的关系就会暴露
That's why you tried to hide it, no matter what.
所以 你无论如何都想隐瞒这件事
Headquarters is investigating this case thoroughly.
本部正在彻底调查此事
They are interviewing the president of Aoyama Kengyou.
还会找青山建业的社长问话
It's only a matter of time before everything comes to light.
真相大白只不过是时间的问题
What have you done?
你干了什么事啊？
Damn it.
可恶
What do you know about me?
你们这群人懂什么？
How many years do you think I have worked for the bank?
你们知道我为这家银行 尽心尽力了多少年吗？
I worked without complaining
我毫无怨言地工作
and got many big loans.
搞定了多少笔巨额融资？
But…
可是
when will they make me a Branch Manager?
他们想过让我晋升为分行经理吗？
They never give me a fair evaluation!
他们甚至没给过我正当的评价
What's wrong with receiving five million yen?
我拿了那五百万又怎样？
Compared to the contribution I made to this bank,
跟我对这家银行做出的贡献相比
it's nothing.
那根本不算什么
With all due respect…
请恕我直言
it is not "nothing."
你这么说是不对的
You were about to cause
你给东京第一银行
over 200 million yen in damages to Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
造成超过两亿日元的损失
What's more,
而且
you were about to damage something that is
你还损害了对银行来说最重视的东西
most important to a bank. Trust.
那就是信誉
The person who prevented that
而试图挽救这一切的
was a someone you tried to get rid of just because she's a woman.
是那位你因为她是女性 就想将她除掉的
Ms. Maehara.
前原小姐
-Shut up! -No, I won't!
-住嘴！ -我不要！
Ms. Maehara gave her best to produce results despite
前原小姐不管如何被羞辱
all the harassment she received.
都尽心尽力工作取得成果
She was even ready to accept the unreasonable grounds for her dispatch.
她甚至愿意接受 那毫不讲理的调职处分
Although you were in the position to lead your subordinates,
身为 课长 你理应带领你的部下
you lent a hand to help a customer with planned bankruptcy.
可是 你却与客户同伙实行计划性破产
That's definitely wrong!
这是大错特错
You just said that one has to take responsibility for what he has done,
你刚刚说必须为自己做过的事负责
to set a good example for the employees.
这样才能给其他职员警惕
Then the person who has to take responsibility right now
那现在最需要负起责任的人
is you, Mr. Komiyama.
是你 小见山课长
Thank you very much.
真的很谢谢你
Aoyama Kengyou?
青山建业？
Mai, isn't this the company you were talking about the other day?
小舞 这个不是你们之前 谈到的那家公司吗？
Yes.
是啊
Many companies go bankrupt these days.
最近好多公司破产啊
We have to be careful too.
我们店也要谨慎一点呢
We are fine, because you are working hard.
我们店有爸爸你那么努力的老板 没问题的啦
Planned bankruptcy, huh?
计划性破产啊？
That's terrible.
真过分啊
But what is planned bankruptcy?
话说 计划性破产是什么啊？
Well, planned bankruptcy is…
计划性破产就是…
Wait a minute. I'm late.
等等 我要迟到了
I will explain it later.
我回来再解释给你听
Thank you for breakfast. See you later!
我吃饱了 出门了
Take care.
路上小心
Bankrupt.
破产
Dad.
爸爸
I will work hard.
要努力啊
As advised by Mr. Shindo,
正如真藤常务所指示的
Mr. Komiyama received a disciplinary dismissal.
小见山课长已经被解雇了
The Branch Manager was transferred to a local branch.
春日经理则被调到其他分行
Everything is settled.
这件事已经解决了
I see.
这样啊
We were able to avoid tarnishing our bank's reputation.
这样做能避免损害银行的信誉啊
Yes. It's all thanks to Executive Director Shindo.
没错 都是多亏了真藤常务的指示
As a business leader, I must get used to handling crisis management.
身为企业的领导 我必须习惯这种危机管理啊
It was a beautiful job.
真是让人敬佩
Ms. Maehara continues to work in Machida Branch.
前原小姐能在町田分行继续工作呢
Good for her.
真是太好了
She was able to avoid the X-mark on her career.
至少她的职业生涯没有留下污点啊
Rather, she got a big plus.
简直是加分了呢
Good morning.
早安
Good morning, Mr. Shibasaki.
-早安 -早安 芝崎次长
I got this from the PR Department. Fresh off the press.
这是我刚从公关部拿到的 《社内报导》
I was interviewed for this.
是采访我的那一期呢
-Let me see. -Yes!
-看看如何 -太好了
Where are you?
你在哪？
Here.
这里
It's so small.
好小
Why is it so small?
怎么这么小篇？
I guess this story came in at the last minute.
应该是临时插入了这则新闻吧？
I see.
这样啊
Look at last month's issue. It was a full-page spread.
上个月的特辑可是整整两页啊
Try next time.
算了 还有下次嘛
I was defeated by a bear.
我居然输给了一只熊
They should have added one more page.
他门多加一页就可以了啊
They interviewed me for 30 minutes.
他们访问了我30分钟呢
It's about three lines.
怎么只登出来三行？
Why?
为什么？
Ex-wife?
前妻？
I'm Yumi Ishihara.
我叫石原由美 初次见面
-Loan? -I thought I'd ask your bank.
-融资？ -不如找你们银行好了
Aoi is hiding something from us.
青井在隐瞒什么？
Why do you defend him?
你为什么要袒护他？
He's my friend.
他是我的朋友
Can't you see that Mr. Soma is suffering?
你不知道相马也很难受吗？
Shut up, Hanasaki.
住嘴 花琦
That's wrong!
这是大错特错